Guide to the Barbara Bogart and Anthony LoCicero Papers, 1946-1970 CTC.1993.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Barbara Bogart and Anthony LoCicero Papers
1946-1970
ULS Archives & Special Collections
LoCicero, Anthony
Bogart, Barbara
CTC.1993.01
2 Linear Feet (3 boxes)
Barbara Bogart and her husband, Anthony LoCicero, were burlesque theatre performers from 1940 through their retirement in 1970. This collection contains photos, skits, newspaper clippings, programs, and correspondence related to both of the careers of Bogart and LoCierco and burlesque theatre in general.
Arrangement
Series I. Photographs
Series II. Burlesque Skits
Series III. Correspondence
Series IV. General Burlesque Theatre Materials
Series V. The Drunkard Materials
Series VI. Oversized Materials
Biography
Barbara Bogart was born in New York City on March 22, 1908. During her childhood, her family returned to her father Andrew's native San Francisco where he was principal tenor with the Tivoli Opera Company. Barbara was sent to Paris after graduation to study voice, piano, and language for several years. Upon leaving Europe, she traveled extensively on freighters throughout the south and central Pacific, as well as Asia. In addition to her musical talents, Bogart was a prolific writer. During her life she authored many plays, poems, two unpublished novels, short stories, and a weekly series of travel articles for the Russian River News. Sometime in 1940, she joined the cast of The Drunkard at the Green Street Music Hall in San Francisco, where she met Anthony LoCicero.
Anthony LoCicero was born in Italy on March 10, 1911. His family immigrated to New York and Anthony began his career in theatre as a magician's assistant at age 15, and went on to appear in vaudeville and burlesque productions. During the late 1930's or early 1940's, he came to San Francisco and became part of the cast of The Drunkard. Anthony LoCicero and Barbara Bogart were married in San Francisco in 1942, and continued their work in The Drunkard.
The Drunkard was a comical adaptation of the Victorian temperance melodrama, Ten Nights in a Barroom. Barbara wrote the music for this production, and also included various additions and revisions to the script. Her principal role was that of Mary Wilson, the play's heroine, while Anthony generally played the villain of the piece and also became the show's producer. The show ran in San Francisco throughout the war years and then was taken on the road throughout California and the West. It was an unqualified success breaking records in many cities for the number of weeks that it ran. Advertisers billed it as a "3 Hour Laff Riot", and the performers played up the melodrama, actively encouraging audience participation. Even the advertisements urged viewers to "Hiss the Villain!" In addition, sandwiches, snacks, and beer were often served at performances. An olio of various vaudeville and burlesque skits accompanied the main production.
The Drunkard's popularity had dimmed by the 1960's, but Anthony remained in show business and performed frequent stints as the straight man in comedy acts. Barbara would occasionally sell tickets at whichever theatre Tony was performing, but had primarily returned to her writing. The couple officially retired in the 1970's and moved to a small cottage in rural Cazadero, California where they lived until their deaths. Anthony LoCicero died May 9, 1987 and Barbara Bogart on Oct 21 of the same year.
Scope and Content Notes
These papers consist primarily of photos, burlesque skits, clippings, programs, drawings, and correspondence. The material ranges in date from LoCicero and Bogart's early days with "The Drunkard" in 1946 to their retirement in the 1970's. Items in the collection include both material generated from their years starring in "The Drunkard" (clippings, programs, etc.) and material collected by Anthony LoCicero pertaining to burlesque in general (skits, photos, articles.) Although small, the collection offers a rare look into the world of burlesque theatre, during its heyday and through its' declining years.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These records were gift of Sewall Bogart in 1993.
Previous Citation
Barbara Bogart and Anthony LoCicero Papers, 1946-1970, CTC.1993.01, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Barbara Bogart and Anthony LoCicero Papers, 1946-1970, CTC.28, Curtis Theatre Collection, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Actors and actresses; Theater; Dramatists; Theater -- California -- San Francisco; Vaudeville -- United States; Burlesques; Burlesque (Theater) -- United States; Bogart, Barbara; LoCicero, Anthony
- Photographs, I.
  Scope and Contents note
  Series I contains three categories of photographs. The first category contains autographed photographs of burlesque performers. The second group contains theatre marquee photos. The final grouping contains unautographed and unidentified photos. Each group of photos are in alphabetical order.
  - Angel, Cindy (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bell, Virginia (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bits of Nonsense (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Briston, Ginger (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Darnell, Sherry (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Dawn, Gay (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - DeeAnn (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - DelRey, Dolores (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Domay (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - DuBois, Lotus (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Knight, Sharon (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Kolb, Ray R. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - LaFemme, Lori (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Long, Brandy (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Martin, Maxine (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Manville, Anita (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Marvou (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Milo, Anita (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Powell, Pepper (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Ravell, Rita (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Red, T.N.T. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Rose, Hermie (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Satana, Tura (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Simone (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - St. Cyr, Lili (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Storm, Tempest (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Waggin, Patti (2) (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Winds, Gail (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Yvette, Yvonne (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Unidentified (6) (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Babcock Theatre, Helena MT (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Century Theatre, Oakland CA (2) (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Metropolitan Theatre, Seattle WA (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Montana Theatre, Butte MT (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Orpheum Theatre, Pocatella ID (2) (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Paramount Theatre, Billings MT (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Strand Theatre, location unknown (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Temple Theatre, Tacoma WA (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Wilma Theatre, Missoula MT (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Bird, Billie (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Bogart, Barbara LoCicero, Anthony (26) (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Dowton, Bill (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Fritcher,Charlie (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Gordon, Phyllis (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - King, Higgy (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Little, Jack Falls (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Unidentified (10) (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Burlesque Skits, II.
  This series consists of short burlesque skits. These are typescripts of short comedic scenes that may or may not have been performed in burlesque productions. All skits are preservation photocopies. To use the original materials please contact the Curator of the Curtis Theatre Collection.
  - "Audience Bit" (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Audience Bit" version 2" (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Bartender Address" (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Carrie Potts, The Chamber Maid" (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Carrie Potts.." version 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - "Haunted House" (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Lady Barber" (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - "Lady Barber" version 2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Park the Car" (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - "Prickly Heat" (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Pullman Train" (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Ten Times Smarter" (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - "Three Wishes (Potato Masher)" (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "Traffic Cop" (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Trolley Car, The" (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Undertaker Parlor" (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Bound Volume of 119 skits (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, III.
  The Correspondence file is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. These letters and telegrams are from the friends and business associates of Barbara Bogart and Anthony LoCicero. The subject matter of the letters includes information about booking and planning of productions to reminiscing with old friends who were also involved with burlesque theatre.
  - 16th St. Follies, contract (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - American Guild of Variety Artists (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
  - Berge, James MD (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bryan Engel Circuit, contract (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Davenport, Del (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Film Art Corporation, contract (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Jess Mack Agency (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Kolb, Ray R. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Manlove, Dudley (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Martin, Gerry (Box 2, Folder 28)
- General Burlesque Theatre Materials, IV.
  This series contains several burlesque theatre magazines, programs, and other ephemeral material.
  - Pay Receipts (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Burlesque show scene lists, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - The Night They Raided Minsky's, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Calvalcade of Burlesque, v.1, no.2., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - A Pictorial History of Burlesque From A to Z, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Program: "Marla Wyman in Person" (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Theatrical Variety Showcase v.1, no.3. April, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Seattle vol.3, no.32. Nov., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Love and Peace. Lysistrata adaptation by A. LoCicero (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - American Guild of Variety Artists convention program, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- The Drunkard Materials, V.
  The materials in this series document the production of The Drunkard that Barbara Bogart and Anthony LoCicero performed in for many years all over the country. All scrapbooks and clippings are preservation photocopies. To use the original materials please contact the Curator of the Curtis Theatre Collection.
  - Scrapbook 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Misc. newspaper clippings (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Programs (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Music score (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Oversize Materials, VI.
  Series VI is made up of oversized illustrations and photographs.
  - Pastel caricature of A. LoCicero (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Pen and ink drawing of A. LoCicero, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Photo of Bogart and LoCicero from The Drunkard (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Photo of B. Bogart (Box 3, Folder 9)